Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Awkward silence.
Sheldon on his phone.
No touching.
Somebody's having date night.
It's actually steamier
than it looks.
Sheldon's looking up the phallic
symbolism of root vegetables
in Renaissance paintings.
Oh, no, I got bored
with that.
I'm just browsing
cuticle scissors on Amazon.
How do you
not tear off his clothes
and take him right here
on this table?
If you do that, I'll scream.
Sheldon, I have some
exciting news to tell you.
That makes two of us.
My new cuticle scissors
will be here
in one to two business days.
Come on, one.
I've been invited to
consult on an experiment
at your university
for a few months.
Isn't that great?
We could have lunch together.
We could carpool.
You know, riding with Leonard
has gotten
a little tedious lately.
Th-The only car game he ever
wants to play is the Quiet Game.
And he's terrible at it.
I always win.
So, you're okay with this?
Well, why wouldn't I be?
Well, this project
would have us working
in close proximity
to one another.
And there's the vulgar adage
that one should not
defecate where one eats.
My father used to say
that all the time.
That and, um, "Who does one
have to orally gratify
to get a drink around here?"
But what does that have to do
with you working
at the university?
Sheldon, "Don't defecate
where you eat,"
means don't have a
romantic relationship
in the workplace.
Really?
Yes.
Huh.
Yeah, I always
took it literally.
That's why I have never
once moved my bowels
in this or any restaurant.
Hmm.
I'm relieved that you
don't have a problem
with us working together.
Not as relieved
as I'm about to be.
It's a brave new world,
little lady.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
♪ The Big Bang Theory 7x05 ♪
The Workplace Proximity
Original Air Date on October 17, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
Are you crazy?
You don't want
your girlfriend
at work with you.
Hell Clam.
Why not?
Hairy Fairy.
I think it could be romantic.
You know, my parents met
at his place of work.
Your father's a gynecologist.
I know.
What started as a pap smear
turned into a date.
Which turned
into her working there,
which turned into marriage,
which then turned into hatred,
which continues to this day.
Two-Eyed Cyclops.
Would you please tell him
this isn't a good idea?
No, no, I think it'll be great.
Maybe next time he gets
conjunctivitis at work,
she can hold his head and try
to put the drops in his eyes.
Giant baby.
That's a Raging Ogre.
Yeah, I know.
I'm just saying, I'd never want
to work with Bernadette.
Can you imagine seeing
someone all day long
and then you're
supposed to hang out
with them after work, too?
Hold on. We do
that all the time.
You and I work together
and play together.
Yeah, I know, and it drove me
into the arms of another woman.
Bipolar Bear.
Well, I appreciate your concern,
but I won't be seeing any more
of Amy than I already do.
I assume we'll deduct
any extra time we spend together
at work from our weekly quota.
Please let me be there
when you tell her that.
Why? So you can see the
look on Amy's face
when she hears
my top-notch idea?
Please, oh, please,
just let me be there.
So, Amy, what are you gonna
be working on at Caltech?
I'm leading a study to see
if deficiency of the
monoamine oxidase enzyme
leads to paralyzing
fear in monkeys.
Oh.
If they're anything like humans,
the answer's yes.
Wait, you've-you've done
this experiment on humans?
You mean like death row inmates
with nothing to lose?
No, that would be unethical.
You know,
not a lot of people know this,
but the monoamine oxidase enzyme
was discovered by a woman,
Mary Bernheim.
That's right.
My phone is just
as smart as you guys.
Amy, Bernadette, Penny.
Amy, Bernadette,
Penny.
Amy, Bernadette, Penny.
He's never gonna
stop doing that, is he?
I don't mind.
I'm hoping to put
his love of repetition
to good use someday.
Hi. Um...
I've reconsidered.
Uh, you can't work
where I work.
Enjoy the rest
of your evening.
Sheldon.
I-I already signed
the contract.
I cashed a check.
Mmm... you are not going
to come out of
this looking good.
Sheldon,
I don't understand.
I thought you said
you were fine with it.
Well, I was.
But that was before
Howard explained to me
how awful it would be
if he had to work
with his significant other.
He said what?
Now, don't be insulted.
He just thinks too much of you
would be mind-numbingly tedious.
Excuse me, I need to have
a chat with my husband.
Yeah, well, now,
well... keep it short.
Fr-From what I gather,
brevity is your friend.
So, are we good here?
No, we're not good here.
I am working on this project.
Yeah, and you can't tell her
what she can and cannot do.
Last week, you told Leonard
he couldn't wear
his Wookiee jacket
out in public.
That's different.
I'm not going to the mall
with someone dressed
dumb space bear.
Sheldon, you don't have to worry
about me bothering you.
I'll be in a different building.
And we don't even have
to have lunch together.
Really?
Yes. Before all things,
I'm a scientist.
I'm just there to do my work
and, with a little luck,
scare the living crap
out of some monkeys.
Hmm.
You sure your mothlike
personality won't be drawn
to this blazing fire
that is myself?
More and more sure.
Well, then, you
have my permission.
I didn't ask
for your permission.
Too late. No backsies.
No, no, listen to me.
Sheldon misunderstood.
What I meant was,
if we worked together,
there'd be too much
of me for you,
not the other way around.
Howard, if you're going
to lie to your wife,
don't start the sentence
with "Sheldon misunderstood."
That's a dead giveaway.
Well?
Okay, fine.
I did say that,
and I think it's true.
I think if we worked together
and lived together,
we'd get sick of each other.
Yeah, but to be fair,
he only said the part
about him
getting sick of you.
For the love of God, why?!
What exactly do you
think you'd get sick of?
His only options here
are to fake a heart attack
or have a real one.
It-it's nothing
in particular. I...
Is it my voice?
Am I too bossy?
What...?
My arm is feeling numb.
Nailed it.
That's the wrong arm for
a heart attack, doofus.
My point is, I'm sure
there are things about me
that would drive you crazy
if you had to deal
with them all day long.
Like looking me in the
eye and lying to me?
Oh, well, come on, I just...
Where am I supposed to
look when I lie to you?
Find somewhere else
to sleep tonight.
Oh, Bernie...
If it makes you feel any better,
Amy and I are fine.
I mean, really good.
So, boys, how was
the pajama party?
You guys jump on the bed
and sing into hair brushes?
It wasn't a pajama party.
It was just a couple of bros
hanging out, giggling,
eating cookie dough
and watching Princess Bride.
Please, stop talking.
As you wish.
I mean, you know, Sheldon,
none of this would've happened
if I hadn't tried
to help you.
Uh, it also wouldn't
have happened
if, in the early universe,
hydrogen was a little more
common or a little less common.
This is fun. Your turn.
Gentlemen.
Hey, Amy.
Hello.
That was kind of icy.
You two okay?
Oh, we're fine.
As Howard advised,
she's merely respecting our
professional boundaries.
Smart.
Take relationship advice
from a man
who spent last night
braiding Raj's hair.
Yeah, you make
a good point.
It would appear
I was worried for nothing.
Look at her, desperately wishing
she was over here
at the cool table.
Don't worry, little moth.
The flame will come to you.
Oh, uh...
on the off chance that
Bernadette doesn't call back
and apologize,
how do you feel
about Mexican food
for dinner tonight?
I-I don't know.
Sounds kind of heavy.
That's 'cause you always
fill up on chips.
And this is Dr. Gunderson
from Stockholm.
Ah, Sweden.
Yeah, home of my favorite Muppet
and, uh,
second favorite meatball.
Okay, the Nordic reputation for
lack of humor is well-founded.
Boy, is his name Gunderson
or No-Funderson?
Where are we going
with this, Dr. Cooper?
Oh, please, I'm your boyfriend.
You call me Sheldon.
That's right,
I am in a boy-girl relationship
with this cute little
lump of wool.
Sheldon...
It's a physical
relationship, too.
Hand-holding, hugging...
even on hot days.
Ow.
Okay, here's a new one.
Apparently now
we kick each other
in the shin under the table.
How do you like it
when I do it to you?
Not so much, huh?
Test subject D7,
aka Betsy, fear response study.
Image number one: Frenchman
on bicycle carrying baguettes.
No visible reaction.
Image number two: sousaphone.
Still no reaction.
Okay.
Let's kick things up a notch.
Image number three: crocodile
with a mouthful of monkeys.
Okay, now we're talking.
Dr. Fowler?
What do you want, Sheldon?
Well, I'm done
with work, so...
Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry.
Sorry. Uh...
Better?
Oh, baguettes.
Yes, I like baguettes.
What exactly
are you doing?
Determining baseline fear levels
in capuchin monkeys
by measuring their response
to visual stimuli.
So, goofing off.
As I was saying, I'm done
with work and Leonard's not.
So good news,
you get to take me home.
Play your cards right,
I'll let you drive me
past the lot
where the buses park at night.
I can't leave now, Sheldon.
I'm very busy.
Besides, why would I want
to do you a favor
after the way you treated
me in the cafeteria?
Image number four:
boa constrictor.
What on earth
are you talking about?
My behavior
in the cafeteria
was delightful.
Maybe your friend
Gunderson needs
to head over
to IKEA and assemble
a sense of humor.
You embarrassed me
in front of my colleagues
on my first day here.
Image number five:
kitten in a teacup.
Oh.
Oh... embarrassed you?
You know what?
I don't have time for this.
Find another way home.
I'm starting to get the sense
that you're angry with me.
Really?
What tipped you off?
Couple things, actually.
Your tone of voice,
your body language...
Get out.
Well, now, that.
Image number six:
woman giving birth.
It's 9:00.
Where you been?
Oh, I had to take
the bus home.
Fell asleep and missed my stop.
Oh, no.
Did you know that Los Angeles
has a Little Sri Lanka?
I did not.
Well, I do... now.
They're a lovely people.
Although terrifying when you
wake up face-to-face with them.
If you're hungry, I brought home
some mutton and coconut milk.
Why'd you get that?
You hate lamb.
I was asking for directions.
Apparently, there was
a communication problem.
I thought Amy was gonna
drive you home.
Yeah, I thought so, too,
but she's acting very strangely.
I was discussing it with
a Sri Lankan fellow on the bus,
and he hypothesized
that a tiger may have
recently run across her shadow.
Although he may have just been
trying to drum up business
for his brother-in-law's
witch doctor practice.
Okay, Sheldon, what happened
between you and Amy?
Well, can you believe
she said I embarrassed her?
Yeah.
But you didn't
even hear the details.
Sheldon...
I've known you
a long time,
and I'm going
to tell you this
with all the love
I can possibly muster.
Amy's right.
You're wrong.
But you don't even know...
Doesn't matter.
But, now, but in my defense...
You're not listening
to my side of it.
Okay, fine, Sheldon.
What is your side?
Well...
Nope, got to go with
Amy on this one.
Shrimp was spicy.
You want a TUMS?
You got
the tropical fruit kind?
No, if I buy those, I just
go through them like candy.
Tell me about it.
One time, I swear
I pooped out a stick of chalk.
I'll get it.
Thanks.
Hi.
Oh, hi.
I may have overreacted.
Yeah, well, I didn't
handle it so great, either.
It's just sometimes I feel
like you enjoy spending time
with your friends
more than with me.
That's not true.
It's not?
You spend all day
together at work,
and then you all hang out
at night playing games,
going to the comic book store.
Last week, you two got
a couples massage.
So, when you said you wouldn't
want to spend that much time
with me, it really
hurt my feelings.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, no, I get that.
I'm so sorry.
Starting tomorrow, I am
turning over a new leaf.
Time with you is my
number one priority.
Why tomorrow?
Well, we're real close
to finishing off
the new Batman game.
It is awesome.
Uh, you should probably
go after her.
Should I go after you?
No!
Thanks for getting me
in trouble.
Amy.
Sheldon, what are you
doing here so late?
I couldn't sleep
because I kept thinking
about what happened
earlier between us.
Also, I had one heck
of a bus nap.
Oh, speaking of which,
do you want some mutton
and coconut milk?
No.
Well, I cannot give
this stuff away.
What do you want?
Amy, this isn't easy to say.
All relationships are difficult,
but even more so
when you're in one
with a person who struggles
with everyday
social interactions.
And frankly...
who can strike some people
as being kind of a weirdo.
Sheldon...
you're not a weirdo.
I wasn't speaking about me.
I mean, honestly,
there's no telling
what will set you off.
You know, introducing
myself as your boyfriend.
Giving you the opportunity
to drive me home.
Breaking the ice
with your colleagues
using ethnic humor,
the funniest kind of humor.
What's your point?
My point is, we're a couple.
And...
I like you for who you are.
Quirks and all.
I like you, too.
Well, I should hope so.
I don't see anyone else
banging on this door
to put up with your nonsense.
Not even a good-bye?
You see,
that's the kind of thing
that makes people
think you're weird.
Poor kid.
She just doesn't see it.
I'm not apologizing
to Howard.
He can come beg me
on his knees.
Sheldon, too.
If I see him at work,
I'm just going to ignore him.
All right, don't worry.
I talked to Leonard.
He is gonna sit the guys down
and set them straight.
Laser's warmed up.
Pull!
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player