<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<RINS>
  <priority level="high">
    <us>
      <title> Endless Map </title>
      <desc> The game map should be infinite, randomly generated by the computer. Differently sized rooms connected with corridors. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Character Development </title>
      <desc> The player needs to be able to upgrade their character's skills and abilities. This can happen when enough experience points. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Character Classes </title>
      <desc> There should be 4 playable character classes, capable of surviving alone, but also useful to each other in multiplayer. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Singeplayer Mode </title>
      <desc> The player chooses a class and fights off waves of monsters, trying to get a place in the highscore. He can't save the game and starts over when he dies. </desc>
    </us>
  </priority>
  <priority level ="medium">
    <us>
      <title> Different Map Themes </title>
      <desc> The theme of the game map should change between 2-3 styles randomly every once in a while. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Playing together </title>
      <desc> Description: Players should be able to team up online and play together against the monsters. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Everyone Against Everyone </title>
      <desc> Players can play online on the same map, fightning against each other.</desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Items </title>
      <desc> The player can buy/sell weapons and ammunition from special vending machines. </desc>
    </us>
  </priority>
  <priority level ="low">
    <us>
      <title> Balanced Classes </title>
      <desc> There shouldn't be a class that is too powerful and easily defeats others in multiplayer. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Character Upgrades </title>
      <desc> The player can buy 'cybernetic' upgrades for their character that give special bonuses. </desc>
    </us>
    <us>
      <title> Smart Enemies </title>
      <desc> The monsters won't just run straight into the characters like kamikadzes, they will try to use basic tactics. </desc>
    </us>
  </priority>
  <repo> https://github.com/lz1irq/RINS </repo>
</RINS>
