[ Music plays ]
Man:
Back from the part of Virginia
I was from,
you know, real rural, coal mining...
You didn't get to experience much
in the way of culture.
It was really quiet and easy living,
but you just had nothing to experience.
When something like
the internet came along,
it really changed things
and opened things up a lot.
If you can't be there,
you can at least see it or read about it.
Hey! Hey! I need the phone.
Man:
It was just... Different perspectives and...
And whole different outlooks on life.
[ Crickets chirping ]
[ Music plays ]
Over several years of talking to people online,
there was some of 'em
that actually helped me out,
told me, "why don't you move out this way?
There'll be more opportunities for you."
[ Wings fluttering ]
[ Music plays ]
They decided to
send me some money...
And basically just said, "move".
[ Music plays ]
I was elated,
and at the same time, terrified.
[ Music plays ]
Mom, I'm going away for a while.
I'm going to be going to, uh, Washington.
Man:
I could see that it bothered her,
that I would be moving so far away.
But at the same time,
she was really supportive.
[ Music plays ]
Woman:
The first call we got was in the afternoon.
I remember it clearly.
It seemed so...
Strange to get that particular
type of call on that day.
We don't get a lot of sun here
in the Pacific Northwest...
So you notice it
when it's a nice, sunny day.
It makes you very happy.
And that particular call
made me very unhappy.
So, at some point,
I said, "is this a bestiality case?
Is that what you're trying to tell me?"
And he said, "yes".
And I said, "so what do you need us to do?"
[ Horse whickering ]
[ Music plays ]
Coyote:
Before I even had the concept of being zoo,
I'd had a feeling
that a traditional family life
was something that I would never do.
I don't need
a high level of emotional interaction...
Whether it be human or otherwise.
I function fine, I think.
You could probably ask three zoos
and get three different definitions.
I guess the main thing would be someone that
feels they have a whole lot closer affinity
to non-human animals than their own kind.
It doesn't necessarily exclude caring
for fellow humans and friends
in the same way.
Man:
We talk to quite a few people
all over the world via the internet.
Unfortunately, most of the people
that were part of our little group were white.
But we did have quite
a few other friends who are black.
There was a Hispanic
that came out to visit once.
Actually, a couple times.
I talked to people out of Poland
and Germany and Japan.
I even talked to
soldiers that are currently in Iraq.
This gives them
a chance to kind of connect back
with the old world
that they knew back here...
Even if it's the same old world
that sent them over there
to survive that environment.
[ Music plays ]
Man:
I worked for the same guy since I was 23.
He's a member
of the National Horse Association.
He had some
top-quality show Arabs.
I did the maintenance.
I got paid good.
Clean the stalls.
His tractor would break down or...
Manure spreader would break down
or something like that.
He was gone all the time.
He was going back and forth
from the West Coast to the East Coast,
because he was building
a new home and a ranch there.
If you could grab all the mail
and put it in there, I'd appreciate it.
Also keep the horse...
H:
They were my so-called friends for 20-some years.
If there's anything else,
our cell phones will be on, so...
H:
When this broke loose,
the last thing he said to me,
he told me I was a very bad person.
We were friends for all those years
and all of a sudden I'm no good
just because I love the horses?
[ Music plays ]
Coyote:
On the bus, I've spent a lot of time in thought.
Why am I this way?
There has to be a purpose.
That part, I don't know yet.
Trying to balance
religion and being zoo...
A lot of that is faith.
Growing up Baptist
in a fairly religious household...
I held certain beliefs to my heart.
God doesn't hate anyone.
You treat your fellow man right.
You don't hurt other people.
And for the most part, you'll...
You'll be okay.
H:
I always treated my animals as part of my family.
They ate before I did.
Look at the videos
that they took of the horses.
Did they look neglected?
No.
It's the love of animals.
That's what zoophilia is.
It's just like if you love your wife or your kids.
It's the same thing.
I took better care of my animals
than I ever did care for myself. Look at me.
I'm... Here I am, going to be 53.
Jenny:
When I had a bout with cancer
and felt really, really badly,
There were many nights
that I went down and spent with my horse.
It's just a very comforting feeling.
They do this
little soft, blow-y thing.
And they know that you're there.
And the time passes so fast.
The night is over before you know it.
I could go down there and just hang on her.
She was my strength.
She was my legs.
She was my heart
that wouldn't beat right,
and I could just cry
and talk and hang out.
It was exactly what I needed at the time.
H:
See, I grew up in the city. I'm a city boy.
And I always
wanted to be a farmer.
Well, the job
gave me what I wanted.
As I say, I started when I was 16,
right after my mom died.
Some reason, it just happened one day,
and I kind of liked it.
I didn't even know it was zoophilia
until I got on the internet.
I've been on
the internet since 2002.
That's the first time, ever.
I had AOL to start with.
It was really interesting
to meet all these different people.
And to this day,
they're still friends of mine.
There was never any
money changed hands.
- Hey, what's up, fellas?
- Hey, there.
- How's it going?
- It's going all right. How you guys doing?
H:
There was people offered me money.
Oh, I'm just going
into the country for a while.
You should go to Pioneer Square.
It's going to be crazy, man.
- Oh, maybe. Next time, right?
- Be safe.
H:
No, I wouldn't accept money from anybody,
because then it's prostitution.
That's against the law.
[ Music plays ]
I knew that bestiality wasn't illegal
in the State of Washington.
A lot of the times
they just want to come out and see.
"We want to see if it's possible."
Man:
[ Speaking in foreign language ]
H:
"Maybe I just want to grab a horse by his nuts
and to feel his balls. How do they feel?"
"They're, well, they... They're warm."
The horse is still the biggest thing
out there on the internet.
I'd invite them to my home, you know,
and I'd treat them like
any other person that was in my house.
I did summertime barbecues.
Thanksgiving.
I'd do Christmas dinners.
One year,
we did a turkey and a ham.
The invite was on a weekend
and in the evening.
[ Music plays ]
[ Phone ringing ]
Hello?
Woman: [ On telephone ]
Hey, we're here.
Well, how was your flight?
Woman:
The flight was long, but we're fine. Right now we're getting...
H:
A Friday night, we'd meet
and if I felt like it was okay for you
to come out, I'd let you follow me home.
If I felt like there was something
about you that I didn't like,
I'd say, "we'll meet again",
and I'd never meet with them again.
"We don't do
this right off the bat. Sorry."
When I met Mr. Hands,
we did talk on the phone a little bit.
And that's when he lived in Seattle.
[ Music plays ]
He was basically curious,
like everybody was curious.
And he had a good personality.
So I invited him out.
Coyote:
I was just astounded at the beauty.
You have that wildness,
but then you have civilization too.
They're just kind of meshed together.
Happy Horseman:
Us humans are so conditioned
from the time we are born
to start categorizing.
And even if they're unconscious,
or even subconscious,
we start categorizing.
Animals just not going to do that.
Flight attendant:
We'll be landing in Seattle in just...
Happy Horseman:
You're either a good person or a bad person.
Woman: [ On radio ]
...The biggest of all munitions companies,
Lockheed Martin Corporation,
playing an important behind-the-scenes role
in developing support for
Bush's war with Iraq.
Man: [ On radio ]
Yes, they did.
They played a very influential role in, uh...
In various organizations
that looked like they were simply
public interest,
public education organizations,
but which had long
advocated a war with Iraq
ever since the 1991,
uh, the first war with Iraq.
It's been to their...
That is, war is the business.
What I mean when
I say it's not private enterprise,
is that it's much more like
state socialism.
You have only one customer.
The customer
is not particularly interested
in getting the best
possible use of his money.
He's much more
interested in simply...
Getting the contracts filled.
Moreover, there is
a huge circulation of elites today
in the sense that most
of the operating positions,
appointed positions in the Pentagon today,
are executives
from the military-industrial complex.
Whereas, by contrast,
any number of
the high officials in these companies
are retired high-ranking
American military officers.
Woman: [ On radio ]
Well, I want to thank you
for being with us, Chalmers Johnson.
His piece appears
in this month's... "Harper's".
It's called "War Business:
Squeezing a Profit from the Wreckage in Iraq",
As well as David Bacon whose piece appears
in "Progressive" magazine.
Chalmers Johnson's
piece ends: "this is the future
when war becomes the most profitable..."
[ Music plays ]
H:
I'd get about 8 or 10, 15 people at the house.
Big party, watch movies, play games.
Happy Horseman:
Kind of a potluck supper kind of thing.
Some people would
bring over some beans or chips
and a meat entree or something.
And of course, lots of beer.
And once in a while
there was a few mixed drinks.
It was kind of fun, throwing
all kinds of stuff into the blender
and churning out things
that kind of had a slushy flavour to them,
that about six or seven
of them would knock you on your ass.
You can only put so many
bottles of rum in some of this stuff.
There was no special flashy...
Nothing going on
that was all that strange and unusual.
I mean, this goes on in hundreds
and thousands of places all over the country.
Age was never
really all that important.
As long as you
were old enough to drink,
you weren't senile
and could talk coherently,
conversation would always ensue.
Do you wear boxers or a thong?
[ Laughter ]
Happy Horseman:
It was pretty much a classless society
of our own little small world.
No one had any kind of
different statuses
and who was this and who was that.
There was no alphas and omegas and betas
running around anywhere.
[ Music plays ]
Coyote:
Being able to get away,
just let everything hang.
Anything I can bring up
or want to talk about,
it didn't matter what was on my mind,
these were people I could trust.
I could just let my hair down
and not have to
worry about things.
[ Music plays ]
H:
There was things in him
that he really
didn't want people to know.
He wouldn't tell you.
He wouldn't tell you the truth.
[ Music plays ]
It took me a long time
to find out his real name.
And it was about a year before I knew
Mr. Hands' real name.
It was just always Mr. Hands.
"I go by Mr. Hands."
Man: [ On television ]
Okay, Jim, it was quite a ride,
But we got it done.
Roger. You're five-by, Jim,
and we're sailing free.
Coyote:
The flag and stuff that they put on the moon
and it looks like it's waving in the breeze,
what do you know?
Of course, there's no atmosphere
on the moon at all.
H:
People would come out,
and we'd walk out into the barn
and I'd show them my horses
and I'd show my bulls,
and they'd ask me
different questions about them.
I'd tell them what this
was and what that was.
"How come his legs
look like that?"
"It's because he's resting."
It wasn't the fanciest place
in the world.
It had cows in it,
so there was crap all over the floors.
There was horseshit
all over the floors.
The horses would come in and out,
and the bulls would come in and out.
And it was just, like, "hey, let's go
out to the barn and pester the animals".
"Well, there they are. Go ahead."
"Just be careful, because
if you stand too long in one place,
It's going to happen."
If you just stand there,
they'll walk up behind you
and put their head on your shoulder
and talk to you.
They're going to pick up that pheromone
that your body's putting off,
and they're going to mount you.
If you don't move, you're bred...
[ Chuckling ]
And I mean bred.
There was times that people'd
come over expecting it,
and no, it never happened.
[ Music plays ]
Jenny:
We had one horse that we called Chance
when we brought him in.
He was blind.
And he was in this area where
it was just nothing but blackberry bushes,
so he kept poking himself in the eye.
We ultimately had
to remove both of his eyes,
because he had re-injured himself
so many times trying to forage for food.
I mean, it touched
all of us very deeply.
When we took that horse
to the veterinary hospital,
we were advised to put him down.
But our feeling and
our experience has been
that just because it has
a problem like blindness,
that's not a good enough reason
to just end their life.
[ Airplane roaring ]
Man: [ On radio ]
One of the things we found fascinating about the story
is that the news media in the Puget Sound
would not reveal the name of the victim.
We believe we have
the name of that man.
We talked to somebody
who worked with this guy.
We talked to someone who got a memo
at work about the death of this guy.
We talked to people
who told us that...
Federal employees
were coming in saying
this name was
never, ever, ever to be given out.
Woman:
My name is Pam Roach,
and I'm the State Senator that covers the
area of Enumclaw
and all the lovely area
on the Enumclaw Plateau.
It's a beautiful area, as you can see.
There are a lot of farms, a lot of people
that love to have animals on these farms,
and a great place to raise children.
I could never believe that an animal
would do this on their own.
We don't allow adults
to abuse children sexually.
Children cannot consent.
Children are innocent, and so are animals.
They cannot consent, and they're innocent.
Mrs. Edwards.
Ready to rescue those horses?
Happy Horseman:
This is a nice little town.
It's not the big city.
You don't have to deal with
the hustle, the bustle, and the crime rate.
Mostly you see in the paper,
somebody's trashcan gets knocked over,
or the drunk next-door neighbour comes over
and pissing on their tires.
It was not a town
that had a whole lot going on in it.
It was quiet.
There was a couple
Chinese food restaurants.
There was a Mexican food restaurant
we'd go to quite a bit.
Quite a few different places to go eat at.
You know,
we're not isolated out there.
We liked the rural setting
but you're not, you know,
dropped in the
middle of nowhere.
[ Music plays ]
H:
Him and his ex-wife got along really well.
He talked to her
on the phone all the time.
She seemed like a nice girl.
Since the divorce, they had gotten
to be best of friends.
They were still friends
up until the day he died.
Happy Horseman:
The type of work he did was basically top secret.
H:
I knew what he did.
I knew exactly what he did
and how he went about doing it,
but... It was just
something that we'd discuss
that was never to be talked about.
Happy Horseman:
I think at one time he was very conservative.
After a while things started changing.
Things started opening
up in front of him.
He was going, "you know,
this really doesn't seem right to me.
Something about this
just is... Kind of wrong."
[ Music plays ]
H:
I had a, uh, apple tree...
Fir tree and a weeping willow.
And otherwise
it was all open pasture, all open field.
Happy Horseman:
Occasionally, there'd be some discussion
on some constitutional issues
of basic freedoms
being usurped by certain political parties
who thought that they needed
to control the morality of the world,
and they didn't care
exactly how they got to do it.
[ Music plays ]
H:
When it'd come to work, he was all business.
When he'd come out to the farm,
he was a completely different person.
He'd be relaxed.
He was comfortable.
[ Music plays ]
Jenny:
They were here during that time
for the son to visit his father.
Woman: [ On P.A. ]
Flight number 324 to Seattle will be leaving gate 26A...
Jenny:
You know, here they had come all this way
to have this sort of
normal family vacation.
About halfway through their vacation...
The death happened.
H:
I called him at work
and I said, "are you
going to come out tonight?"
He goes, "no, but I'll
be out next weekend".
I said, "oh, no, you
gotta come out tonight.
There's somebody
here that wants to meet you."
And we argued a little bit over the phone,
and I finally got him to come out.
Well, that was my downfall.
Just irritates me thinking about it.
Turn this thing off... Please.
[ Music plays ]
Happy Horseman:
You're connecting with another intelligent being
who is very happy to...
Participate, be involved.
[ Music plays ]
You're not going to be able
to ask it about the latest Madonna album.
It has no idea what Tolstoy is, or Keats.
You can't discuss the difference
between Monet and Picasso.
It just doesn't exist for their world.
It's a simpler, very plain world.
And for those few moments,
you kind of can get disconnected.
[ Music plays ]
It's a very intense,
wonderful kind of feeling.
I don't think anything
really can kind of compare to it.
There's no pain.
[ Music plays ]
At no time, in any way, shape or form,
has anybody forced,
coerced, drugs, ropes, whatever.
There's no bondage
or anything like that involved in any of this,
Because these are...
These are your friends.
[ Music plays ]
[ Door hinges squeaking ]
[ Door slams shut ]
[ Music plays ]
I had...
Submitted a...
Query regarding another role,
uh, which I didn't get and...
After that, I forgot all about it.
And then about two months later,
I received a e-mail
letting me know that the director had...
Saved my pictures
that I had submitted
and was interested in meeting with me
for the role of cop #1
for a movie, and that's all I knew.
[ Chuckling ]
I met with Rob the next day, and, uh,
I was frantically looking for a place to park,
and I was real...
I was becoming later and later
and I was stressed out, and finally...
I just parked in a,
um, a loading zone,
and I ran down to the...
To where I was supposed to meet Rob, and...
And just let him know.
And he said, "well, um...
[ Clears throat ]
Just go back to your car
and I'll meet you over there."
So I went over there
and stood by my car,
and we started chatting about...
About the movie.
And at that time,
he told me what the
movie was about and...
You know, I was...
It didn't faze me because...
I have, um...
I've seen the best of humanity
and I've also seen
the darkest parts of humanity.
The summer prior to this incident,
I was in a softball
tournament in Enumclaw,
and I had a...
A guy on the opposing team
injured himself in the outfield,
and I actually helped him onto the stretcher
that took him to the very same hospital
where this man died.
And, you know,
that hits kind of close to home.
The cold, harsh, brutal reality
is a man bled to death, okay?
And as I researched my role
and revisited some articles that
I had read a year prior,
and also some new information,
you know, I...
I thought about...
I thought about what was going
through this man's mind
as he was bleeding to death.
And how did he find himself
in this place at this time?
And, uh...
You know, I had the experience
of holding a corpse in my hands
that was a few minutes before
a seven-year-old boy
that had drowned in a swimming pool,
and his last breath was...
Frozen in time on his face.
And his... His eyes were fixed,
and I could see
right down into his mouth,
and it was ghostly white, and it...
At that moment, when I was staring
into those empty eyes
and looking into
the depths of death,
all's I saw was
my own reflection.
And... To be there
at that moment in time,
during that tragedy,
[ Sighing ]
for a little boy that could not be revived,
and ended up dying on Mother's Day,
you know, that...
That's embossed in my heart.
And... And it's... It...
When someone dies, it's...
It's something that I...
I take to heart
because there's nothing trivial about it.
There's people that...
That love that individual,
and they will never see them again.
And that's a tragedy.
[ Helicopter whirring ]
Happy Horseman:
We knew it was going to happen.
But we didn't know when.
[ Music plays ]
H:
The media pushed this thing
so far out of proportion, it's unreal.
Happy Horseman:
How many places do you know of
that actually gets CNN news to go down
and fly a helicopter over the property
just so they can have some footage
for an accidental death?
H:
One day I'm doing just fine,
and the next day I'm an evil person.
There's nothing evil about me.
I wasn't breaking the law.
I had everything going for me
and it all come crashing down around me.
Anchor: [ On TV ]
...Animal cruelty after a bizarre death in King County.
Reporter: [ On TV ]
According to the Sheriff's Department,
the man died from internal bleeding after
allegedly having sex with a horse in Enumclaw.
According to the King County
Sheriff's Office...
Authorities were able to find the farm after the man
was dropped off at a local hospital.
Surveillance cameras traced the vehicle
used back to the farm.
Deputies say they are investigating the possibility
that animal cruelty laws might apply.
H:
We had buckets full of tapes and CDs and stuff.
I wanted to get
the stuff out of the house.
I was scared.
[ Phone ringing ]
Happy Horseman:
We did notice
a very definite change in the phone service.
[ Ringing ]
Happy Horseman:
Picking up the phone, every 15 seconds,
there would be a little blank spot.
Nobody at
either end could hear.
And then it would come
back to normal again.
Every 15 seconds.
And that went on for quite a few days.
[ Banging on door ]
We were actually getting
tracts, religious tracts.
People were trying to save our souls.
[ Music plays ]
Man 1 : [ On phone ]
Hello, dad!
Man 2:
Hello, son!
Man 1:
Hey, dad, you know what?
They... They need to get
this guy's name out there.
What's the guy thinking, screwing a horse?
- [ Laughter ]
-...Find out.
[ Laughter ]
Man 2:
Well, nobody finds out if you live!
Rush Limbaugh: [ On radio ]
To the remaining items in our news digest today:
"people who have..."
This from Olympia, Washington.
"People who have sex with animals
should face felony convictions for animal cruelty",
says a Republican Senator pushing
for a ban on bestiality.
"These animals don't have
the cognitive ability to consent
and that is the case, that we have to be
protecting them", said Pam Roach.
Really, now, I hate to express
my naivete about these kinds of things,
but... Well, no, I don't, actually.
I'm very proud
to be naive about these kinds of things.
But how do they know
the horse didn't consent?
How in the world...
Can this happen without consent?
We're talking... We're...
We're talking about
a human being and a horse.
[ Stammering ]
If... If the horse didn't consent,
then none
of this would have happened.
Happy Horseman:
They're looking for a spark...
To get a shit storm started.
And this provided that spark.
[ Music plays ]
He said, "stop right where you're at.
Put your hands behind you.
You're being arrested for homicide."
And I said, "what? I am?"
"I can't tell you any more.
You've got to come with me."
[ Music plays ]
H:
I had it loaded.
I had it in my mouth.
I was going to blow
the top of my head off.
That's how I felt.
50 calibre rifle.
Black powder.
Can you imagine
what that would have done to me?
[ Grunting on TV ]
[ Inaudible ]
H:
They were investigating a homicide that didn't happen.
[ Grunting continues ]
H:
They assumed it was the horse that killed Mr. Hands.
They assumed that.
[ Grunting/groaning on TV ]
Mr. Hands: [ On TV ]
Oh, God...
H:
It doesn't show anything.
All's it shows is the horse
doing something.
[ Grunting continues ]
Man:
Is that your horse?
Coyote:
In their mind, they don't care
whether it's a filly
underneath them or a human.
You've got something
like a male animal,
pretty much our purpose
on this earth is to procreate.
I don't mean to sound detrimental to males,
but we're here to pass the seed along
that keeps generations going.
So there's always that drive.
[ Moaning ]
Get out of my head!
Happy Horseman:
There were some nutcases in that jail.
Get out of my head!
[ Groaning ]
Happy Horseman:
You're dealing with some very strange mentality.
And they had one guy up in there,
just thinks it's kind of fun
to go around instigating fights.
I've got a couple friends
who are coming here...
We're going to
blow a hole in the walls.
Happy Horseman:
Jeez, this is nuts.
I'm stuck with all these guys in here.
Finally, they took me upstairs
and said, "okay, this is...
This and this and this and this.
And we already know about that.
And this and this and this. Sign here."
"No.
What you've been hearing
is not exactly true."
We were basically
gone for the weekend.
We were not expecting Mr. Hands
to make an appearance at all.
H:
Every time he'd come out to the house,
It was always about the son...
How he's coming along in school.
His writing was getting better.
This went on for hours.
Oh, yeah. He loved his boy.
That was one of the things
he was setting up the house for.
It was for her
to come back and live with him.
So he could be closer to his son.
[ Music plays ]
Coyote:
He was losing blood into his abdominal cavity.
You can have an injury like that
and be bleeding to death internally
and not really feel it.
I don't know if he really understood
that what had happened
was something that was killing him.
Happy Horseman:
He thought that getting married, having kids...
That was going to be
the greatest thing in his life,
and that didn't turn out as great.
Some of the different relationships
he's had, just close friends...
Others, it went further than that...
Some of those didn't turn out so good.
So in a way...
Coming to the ranch was,
"I don't have to impress anybody.
I don't have to really
deal with relationships."
Jenny:
His family had commented to me
that they were shocked when he called
and said, "I bought a horse".
They didn't want
to go onto the property
because they didn't want to have anything to do
with the people that were involved.
But from an estate point of view,
they had these animals that had to be dealt with.
[ Music plays ]
H:
The sheriff gave me seven days to get out.
I already gave my mares away.
I already took my bulls to the auction
and all I had left was Gablar and Strut.
Jenny:
The brother, the father and l
all met in the station
and the police led us out to the property.
We pulled up into the yard
and the police chief drove on.
And that's when I really realized
that he wasn't going to come in with us.
This guy came out and it was extremely obvious
that he was very deeply involved.
The brother just kept
saying, "keep me away from this guy.
Just keep me away from this guy."
He struck us as
a child molester type,
just a really creepy kind of guy.
So I said, "we've come to pick up
one or two horses. Where are they??"
[ Music plays ]
At the time, I thought, "I can't think
through this right now".
So I just turned on
my internal camera, my head cam.
What does that look like?
And what's this barn look like?
And what's this area look like?
He just kept saying, "I'm all torn up over this.
I'm just all torn up over this".
And it was just so not real.
And then he pointed to the ceiling
and there was a kind of a rope thing
with a small noose-looking thing
at the end of this rope,
and he said this is
where he would work the horse.
And I thought, "Whoa.
What do you mean...
'Work a horse'?"
H:
That rope is a training tool.
They're called a high tie.
And what he'd do is
he'd tie the horse's lead rope to that.
And the horse could go around in the pen,
but he couldn't get out.
He was teaching himself how to ride.
Jenny:
Stallions can be very dangerous.
We didn't know what
his interaction had been with humans.
I just spoke quietly to him.
I probably said things like...
"Oh, you're a pretty boy.
It's a beautiful day."
H:
Well, my impression of Jenny is that, uh...
She doesn't know her ass from a hole
in the ground when it comes to a horse.
Period.
She comes across
as being a person
that knows everything
there is about horses,
but to me, she doesn't
know anything about them at all.
[ Horse snorting ]
Even her husband doesn't know
how to handle a horse.
[ Horse whinnying ]
Jenny:
I didn't realize until we got there
that he'd owned two horses.
So I started asking questions
about the other horse.
"What's the status of Strut?"
And he said, "well, I own that horse.
He gave that horse to me".
And I said, "well, show me
your bill of sale".
And he goes, "well, I don't have that".
And I said, "well,
you need a bill of sale".
And then about that time,
this guy shows up in a little truck.
H:
The person that bought Strut is a friend of mine.
And there was a bill of sale
and everything was there.
I don't think if, uh...
Even if I didn't have the paperwork,
I was going to let her take that horse.
Jenny:
But then a weird thing happened.
This little mini
came up and got up under
and started giving
the stallion a blow job.
It was the strangest thing I've ever seen.
Ever.
[ Music plays ]
Happy Horseman:
I didn't get home until much, much later that evening
and hadn't really paid too much
attention to Mr. Hands.
We did acknowledge
each other's existence.
H:
I had to leave. My boss was out of town
and I was taking care
of his horses at his place.
It was around
10:00, 11:00 o'clock,
and usually I feed them at 8:00 o'clock.
I went over there ; I'd been drinking.
But I was hungry,
so I ate something.
Well, that was my downfall,
because as soon as I eat, I just pass out.
Happy Horseman:
Something bad happened out there.
I don't think Mr. Hands
knew this particular animal very much.
And I don't think the gentleman
that was with him
was really attuned
to that animal, as well.
It wasn't until around
5:15, 5:20 in the morning
that he made the announcement
that he needed to go to the hospital right away.
If I had just the slightest inclination
that something was wrong,
he would have ended up in
the hospital immediately.
H:
He could have been out in the barn with his horse.
He could have been out
there with my horse.
I'm not saying he was,
I'm not saying he wasn't.
Like I said, I was not there.
Happy Horseman:
"Please don't let this happen."
And then I noticed that his lips
were changing colour.
Woman:
Sir?
- [ car door opens ]
- Sir!
I'm not getting a pulse. Code!
H:
You need to go out in the pasture with a bunch of horses.
They're going to come to you.
They're going
to see who you are.
Then see what they do to you.
Mr. Hands: [ Whispering ]
I can't think about it anymore.
H:
That's what you need to do.
Mr. Hands: [ Whispering ]
...In the "C" direction multiplied by the exponent,
the irrational number that constant can...
[ Shouting ]
Now it's good news!
[ Whispering ]
Multiplied by "C" minus the tangent.
[ Whinnying ]
I can't just stop working. I mean...
God. And I can't do it. I cannot...
The mean is predicted to have elliptical
Gaussian pattern diffracted...
H:
I know another guy that used to work at the Black Hole...
Woman: [ On two-way radio ]
Does he have any identification?
H:
The same place that Mr. Hands did.
He had made a ripple...
So they fired him.
Mr. Hands, he was building antennas.
He told me all about this one he just did
and how it worked really well.
And they were really proud
of him at the company.
He was liking that.
But I think what really he wanted to do
was get away from that.
He wanted to be a farmer.
He wanted to be like me.
[ Monitors beeping ]
[ Music plays ]
[ Rapid beeping ]
[ Flatline beep ]
[ Fire crackling ]
H:
Mount Rainier is actually a beautiful mountain.
There's a picture
of a deer head on the side.
There's the throat and the horns.
Once I found it,
I couldn't see Mount Rainier for years.
All I could see was that deer head.
It took me a long time to look
around that deer head
to see Mount Rainier again.
Jenny:
I know he really loved his brother.
I think that's why he kept
talking about it and talking about it.
He told me a lot about the things that
they found in the apartment.
He was really
mulling it over in his mind.
And he actually found...
A cast of Strut's penis.
Man: [ on radio ]
All right, we did a lot of research,
we got a lot of phone calls.
We pulled together
a lot of information.
And here is what we have:
we have an employee, now deceased,
who worked at
Boeing Corporation, Named K...
[ Music plays ]
Happy Horseman:
There was nothing
that they could really screw
this down with.
They will just
basically defame you into oblivion.
Your names will be posted
all over the place.
H:
My secret is out now.
Everybody in the world
knows what I did.
I was evil.
I was evil because I...
I had a love for my animals more
than most people do.
"Go away.
We don't want anything to do with you.
Just get out of our sight."
I wanted just to walk away from it
and leave the past in the past.
Because I had it made.
I had the job of a lifetime.
At 50, it's hard to start over again.
I studied Buddhism
for about three years.
It's been around a hell
of a lot longer than God was ever around.
I still chant to this day.
So I got my beads out
and my book out.
You can wish it away...
But you have to concentrate.
I still want to do the farm life.
That's going to be me again.
Happy Horseman:
The sex was just a small component of it.
And by standing there talking to them,
in a way you're kind of connecting to them,
going... "I'm talking to you
on the same level
that you're kind of staring at me,
mammal to mammal."
Coyote:
If I sat down and tried to talk to Mr. Hands' family,
I'd find that rather difficult to do.
I can't even fathom what kind of hurt
that they're feeling
over the whole thing.
H:
I do miss him.
A lot.
[ Music plays ]
Jenny:
We didn't want anybody showing up here
who was part of that circle
who would want to adopt him.
So we made the decision
to geld him that night.
[ Music plays ]
Jenny:
I was trying to understand about this whole issue.
So I started doing some research.
In some of the things I read,
I came across the term zoophilia,
and I started kind of exploring that and, you know,
doing a little bit more research about it.
And it was really interesting to me...
It was just interesting to me
to learn that there are people
who really have a love relationship
for an animal not of their species.
These people were talking
about the extreme and loving care
that they give their animal partner.
I-I don't yet quite know
how I feel about that.
But I'm right at the edge
of being able to understand it.
[ Music plays ]